本字幕由高清电台整理发布，更多高清电影请访问
https://gaoqing.fm
代表时间变异管理局
HUNTER B-15: On behalf of the Time Variance Authority,
我以侵犯神圣时间线的罪名逮捕你
I hereby arrest you for crimes against the Sacred Timeline.
前情提要
很久以前 全知全能的 时间守护者出现了
MISS MINUTES: Long ago, the all-knowing Time-Keepers emerged,
他们创造了神圣时间线
creating and organizing the Sacred Timeline.
有时 会有像你一样的人偏离常规路径
Sometimes, people like you veer off the path.
这些人就是时间犯
We call those Variants.
劳菲森 你有何申辩？
Laufeyson, how do you plead?
-我是莫比乌斯探员 -你在这多长时间了
-I'm Agent Mobius, by the way. -How long have you been here?
我不知道 很难说 时间变异管理局的时间流动不太一样
MOBIUS: I don't know. It's hard to say, time passes differently here in the TVA.
你们在这里走来走去
Now, you parade about
仿佛自己是宇宙中至高无上的仲裁
as if you're the divine arbiters of power in the universe.
无限原石？
LOKI: Infinity Stones?
有些人拿来做镇纸
Some of the guys use 'em as paperweights.
这里是全宇宙最强大的力量吗？
Is this the greatest power in the universe?
我回不去了 是不是？
LOKI: I can't go back, can I? MOBIUS: I can't offer you salvation,
我不能给你救赎
但是也许我可以给你更好的
but maybe I can offer you something better.
一个在逃的时间犯在杀害我们的时间卫士
A fugitive Variant's been killing our Minutemen.
你需要诡计之神来帮你制止他？
And you need the God of Mischief to help you stop him?
为什么是我？
Why me?
因为我们在追捕的时间犯就是...
MOBIUS: The Variant we're hunting is...
你
You.
威斯康星州 奥什科什
1985年
许个愿
CHILD: Make a wish.
你好 怎么回事？
Hi! What's going on?
你们的打扮可不对
You guys aren't dressed right.
那么...
I... So...
发现时间犯 时间变异管理局
MINUTEMAN: Variant detected, Commander.
发现时间犯 指挥官
开始行动
Let's move.
这可是我们的要求
Some of us need this, you know.
还没有关连事件能量 长官
MINUTEMAN: No nexus energy yet, ma'am.
HUNTER C-20: It's a trap. Watch your backs!
这是个陷阱 小心背后
我的主人 亲爱的女士们 欢迎前来
ANNOUNCER: My lords, my ladies, welcome
欢迎在城堡里加入我们的行列
and thank you for joining us, here at the castle.
请在座位上坐好 一场大战即将开始
Please, settle into your seats for a great battle is about to commence.
奖励是什么？我们的公主
The prize? Our princess.
究竟是邪恶的一方获胜 还是我们能坚持到英雄降临
Will evil prevail, or are we holding out for a hero?
指挥官？
MINUTEMAN: Commander?
Where have all the good men gone And where are all the Gods?
Where's the streetwise Hercules to fight...
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
这样才好玩
Having some fun.
Isn't there a white knight Upon a fiery steed?
Late at night, I toss and I turn And I dream of what I need
I need a hero
I'm holding out for a hero Till the end of the night
He's gotta be strong And he's gotta be fast
And he's gotta be fresh from the fight
I need a hero
I'm holding out for a hero 'Till the morning light
运行程序 - 时间门
He's gotta be sure and it's gotta be soon
And he's gotta be larger than life
I need a hero!
力量 性能 质量
MISS MINUTES: Okay, y'all, let's review what we've learned.
好的 各位 让我们来回顾一下咱们学到的
当关连事件分支超出红线时 会发生什么？
What happens when a nexus event branches past red line?
非常糟糕的事情
Very bad things.
正经点 洛基 是什么？
Come on, Loki. What is it?
It's when the TVA can no longer reset a nexus event.
时间变异管理局将无法 重置关连事件
行了吗？太无聊了
Okay? Boring.
没错 而且那会导致时间线的毁灭
Right. And that would lead to the destruction of the timeline
还有我们所知的现实的崩溃
and the collapse of reality as we know it.
你能听到我说话吗？
Can you hear me?
你是录制好的 还是有生命的？
Are you a recording? Or are you alive?
Uh, sorta both.
两者都是吧
Ah.
Watch it! Where's your manners?
注意点 懂不懂礼貌？
Oh! Hey! Quit it!
住手
你这个坏人 混蛋
That is not nice. Jerk.
-别躲 -训练怎么样？
-You can't hide... -MOBIUS: Training goin' well?
-挺好的 -那是我的摩托艇杂志吗？
-Yeah. -Is that my jet ski magazine?
给我放下 穿上衣服
Put it down. Gear up.
发生袭击了 跟我来
There's been an attack. Let's go.
穿上
Put it on.
不错呀 挺帅
Good. Yeah. Smart.
威斯康星州 奥什科什 - 1985年 威胁级别 高
C-20和她的小队一起失联了
C-20 and her team went dark
就在他们进入1985年的分支后不久
shortly after they jumped into the 1985 branch.
所有迹象都指向又一次伏击
All signs point to another ambush.
我们收集了足够多的现世光环证明 就是时间犯洛基
We've grabbed enough temporal aura to know it's our Loki Variant.
但是是什么类型的洛基 还不得而知
But which kind of Loki, remains unknown.
肯定是更低等的
They're the lesser kind, to be clear.
Let me see the back of that jacket.
给我看看你的衣服背面
时间犯
Hmm.
很隐蔽啊 干得好
Very subtle. Well done.
我可不想让大家忘了你的身份
I don't want anybody out there to forget what you are.
你们抓住杀人凶手的救命稻草？
Oh, your only hope of capturing a murderer?
当然不是 你是个巨大的错误
No. A cosmic mistake.
-够了 -谢谢
-That's enough. -Lovely.
咱们说好了
MOBIUS: Here's the deal.
当我们进入分支时
When we get out on the branch,
我们要找的不只是时间罪犯
we're not just looking for a Time Criminal.
还有洛基的踪迹
We're looking for a Loki.
这家伙的变异体
A variation of this guy.
他是我们的老对手
A type we should all be very familiar with,
因为时间变异管理局 已经裁剪过这家伙很多次了
because the TVA has pruned a lotta these guys,
比其他任何时间犯都要多
almost more than any other Variant.
他们各不相同
And no two are alike.
有时外貌差别不大 有时差别挺大
Slight differences in appearances, or not so slight.
虽然他们能力不同 但是基本是这几样
Different powers, although, powers, generally include
变幻外形 制造幻象 还有我最欣赏的...
shape-shifting, illusion-projection, and my favorite...
那是制造分身
Duplication-casting.
是制造幻象
Illusion-projection.
不对 这两个能力完全不同
No, they're two completely different powers.
怎么不同了
How?
制造幻象是从外部描绘细节图像
Illusion-projection involves depicting a detailed image from outside oneself,
是外部世界能分辨的
which is perceptible in the external world,
而制造分身则需要
whereas duplication-casting entails recreating
在现有环境里完全复制整个身体
an exact facsimile of one's own body in its present circumstance,
可以说是分子结构的真实镜像
which acts as a true holographic mirror of its molecular structure.
但是这你们都知道了
But you already knew that.
好吧 喘口气 我知道了
Okay, take a breath. Noted.
我们要分成两队 我和洛基教授也要去
We're gonna break into two teams, including myself and Professor Loki.
为什么？
Why?
因为不管这个时间犯是谁 我们一直找不到他
Because whoever this Variant is, we haven't been able to find him.
所以这次得专家出场
So let's bring in an expert.
那就是我了
That's me.
-我有武器吗？ -没有
-Do I get a weapon? -Nah.
好吧 我又能用魔法了 没人担心吗？
Well, I'll have my magic back. Is no one concerned about that?
-担心什么？ -担心我背叛你
-Of what? -Me betraying you.
-没有 -为什么没有？
-No. -Why not?
你知道我们总能抓住你
You know that we can catch you.
而且背叛我们你还怎么接近时间守护者？
And how's betraying us gonna get you any closer to the Time-Keepers?
我有机会见到时间守护者？
An audience with the Time-Keepers is on the table?
你可以试试
Keep that focus.
已到达关连事件标记峰值 长官
Apex of nexus signature located, ma'am.
我有个问题
Let me ask you this,
为什么我们不能回到攻击发生之前
why don't we just travel back to before the attack,
回到时间犯最初出现的时候？
when the Variant first arrives?
关连事件导致时间流不稳定
Nexus events destabilize the time flow.
这个分支还在不断变化加剧 所以你只能按照实际时间出现
This branch is still changing and growing, so you gotta show up in real time.
该看的训练视频你看了吗？
Did you watch any of the training videos you were supposed to?
我尽可能地忍着看了
Well, as many as I could stand.
时间变异管理局的这些宣传材料太无聊了
Your TVA propaganda is exhausting.
那这些是干什么的？
And what do these do?
重置器可以裁剪掉分支时间线上受影响的区域
Reset charges prune the affected radius of a branched timeline,
这样时间就可以自愈
allowing time to heal all its wounds.
说白了就是
Which sounds like a nice way
把周围一切解体 换个好听的说法
of saying disintegrate everything in its vicinity.
他上道了
He's on it.
我可是看了视频的
I watched the videos.
多少看了点吧
I mean, some of them.
他开始挟持人质了？
HUNTER B-15: So he's taking hostages now?
这个时间犯从来没有挟持过人质
MOBIUS: The Variant's never taken a hostage before.
也许他开始变本加厉了
HUNTER B-15: Maybe he's upping his game.
要不就是他裁剪了她
MINUTEMAN: Or he pruned her.
洛基肯定打不过C-20
HUNTER B-15: A Loki couldn't have gotten the jump on C-20.
其实我觉得你低估了...
I think you underestimate, actually...
散开队形 开始搜寻
Fan out and search for her.
加快速度
And hurry up,
我们离红线还差三格
we're at three units until red line.
-开始吧 她说的没错 -来吧
MINUTEMAN: Let's go. She's right. MOBIUS: Come on.
等等
Wait...
你们要是离开这个帐篷 就会和他们下场一样
If you leave this tent, you'll end up like them.
你发现什么了？
What do you see?
我发现了一个阴谋
I see a scheme,
在那个阴谋里 我发现了我自己
and in that scheme, I see myself.
阿斯加德有句谚语
We have a saying in Asgard,
狼耳所现之处 狼牙伺机而动
"Where there are wolf's ears, wolf's teeth are near."
意思是你要时刻警惕周围的环境
It means to be aware of your surroundings.
这其实很荒谬 因为我们族人天生就是 上当受骗的笨蛋
Which is absurd, because my people are, by nature, gullible fools.
我作为诡计之神
A trait that I, the God of Mischief,
一次又一次地利用他们的这个弱点 一听就知道
exploited time and time again simply by listening.
我的牙齿很锐利 但是我的耳朵更加锐利
My teeth were sharp, but my ears even sharper.
我们没有时间了 莫比乌斯
We're running out of time, Mobius.
等等 给他一个机会
Hold it. Just give him a chance.
你让我想起了他们
LOKI: You remind me of them.
时间变异管理局和阿斯加德的众神 是一路货色
The Time Variance Authority and the gods of Asgard, one and the same.
醉心于权力 却无视真相
Drunk with power, blinded to the truth.
那些你低估的人会吞噬你
Those you underestimate will devour you.
你低估我
You underestimate me,
就像你低估这个低等洛基一样
just as you underestimate this lesser Loki.
这就是为什么你们一次又一次地 自投罗网
Which is why, you walk into one wolf's mouth after another.
只剩两格了 他这是浪费时间
--Two units. He is wasting our time.
好吧 快点 洛基 长话短说
Okay. Come on, Loki, make a long story short.
我们得找到C-20
HUNTER B-15: We need to look for C-20.
这就是时间犯的目的
That's exactly what the Variant wants you to do.
这是个圈套 他就在帐篷外边等着你
It's a trap. He's waiting for you outside this tent.
我要收回重置器吗？
Should I secure the reset charges?
不用 他要找的是我 我是他计划的关键
No. He wants me. I'm the key to his plan.
-他知道我更强大 -就快剩一格了
-He knows that I'm stronger. -Almost one unit.
而且他非常确定 我们一起 可以推翻并且掌管时间变异管理局
And he rightly believes that together we can overthrow and rule the TVA.
但是那不是我想要的 我有了一个新的目标
But that's not what I want. I have a new purpose.
我是神圣时间线的奴仆
I'm a servant of the Sacred Timeline.
我现在知道了他的策略
And knowing what I now know about his tactics,
我可以把这个时间犯抓回来
I can deliver you the Variant,
但是我需要保证
but I need assurances.
什么保证？
Yeah?
保证任务完成的那一刻
Assurances that I won't be completely disintegrated
我不会被完全解体
the moment the job has been done.
好啊
Right...
咱们得立刻去见时间守护者
We'll need to speak to the Time-Keepers at once.
他们所处的危险远超想象
They're in graver danger than we realized.
他在说谎 逗我们玩呢
He's lying. Just playing games.
外面根本没人
There's no one out there.
重置时间线
HUNTER B-15: Reset the timeline.
我差点就信了
You had me for a second.
我的耳朵也很锐利
My ears are sharp too.
时间线重置
追捕者C-20 失踪
是我的错觉吗 还是这个办公室 变得越来越豪华了？
MOBIUS: Is it just me, or does this office keep getting better and better?
那个是从哪弄来的 那个下雪水晶球？
Where'd you get that one, the snow globe?
这些真不错
I love those.
我不记得带回来过那个盒子
I don't remember bringing back that case.
为我工作的分析师又不止你一个
You're not the only analyst working for me.
但是我是不是你最喜欢的那个？
But, would you say, maybe, I'm your favorite one?
为什么你要把我的战利品都拿走？
And why do you get to keep all the trophies from my cases in here?
你不知道我喜欢用那个溜冰鞋
You don't think I'd love having that roller skate
来美化我的书架吗？
there sprucing up my cubicle?
因为那些行动是我负责的
Because I approve the missions.
说得没错
Good point.
正好 咱们聊聊你刚刚搞砸的那个行动吧
Speaking of which, let's talk about the one you just botched.
咱们聊天可少不了这个
You might need this for our discussion.
再多点就更好了
I hope it's a double.
这个时间犯是 我行我素 冥顽不化 难以预料
This Variant is... "Insubordinate, stubborn, unpredictable."
听上去和某人一样
Sounds like someone else I know.
我也觉得和某人很像
I was just thinking it sounds like someone I know.
-莫比乌斯？ -怎么？
-Mobius? -What?
那些水印原来就有
Those rings were already there.
都是你弄的
And they're all from you.
没准是另一个你喜欢的分析师弄的
Maybe it's from your other favorite analyst.
听着 拉芙娜 我很抱歉
Listen, Ravonna, I'm sorry.
我知道我对待
I realize that my, you know,
这个洛基的方式有争议 但是...
methods with this Loki are controversial, but...
把一个危险的时间犯带去行动是有争议的
Towing a dangerous Variant into the field is controversial.
对 今天就并非完全如我所愿
Yeah, it didn't go exactly the way I wanted it to today,
但是我们发现了一点
but here's what we did find out.
这个时间犯喜欢拖延时间
The Variant likes to stall for time,
最终我们肯定会抓住另一个 有同样习惯的人
and, eventually, we'll catch the other one doing the same thing.
因为了解这个洛基能够帮助我接近
Because understanding this Loki helps me get closer
我们正在追捕的那个 不是吗？
to the one we're chasing. Right?
我知道你是个心慈手软的人
Look, I know you have a soft spot for broken things.
-我不这么觉得 -你就是这样
-I don't think so. -Yes, you do.
但是洛基就是个邪恶的 满嘴谎言的祸害
But Loki is an evil, lying scourge.
他在神圣时间线上就是这种货色
That is the part he plays on the Sacred Timeline.
也许他想改头换面呢
Maybe he wants to mix it up.
有时你也会厌倦一成不变的
Sometimes you get tired of playing the same part.
这有可能吗？他能改变吗？
Is that possible? He can change?
除非时间守护者裁决 否则不可能
Not unless the Time-Keepers decree it.
到那个时候 该怎么样就怎么样
And then, it shall be so.
时间守护者那边怎么样？
- And how are the old Time-Keepers? -
你觉得呢？
How do you think?
我不知道 因为我从来没见过他们
I don't know. 'Cause I've never met 'em.
谢天谢地 虽然我不该这么说
Thankfully. Although, I shouldn't say that.
它看上去...
That one looks...
时间守护者监控着这个案件的每个环节
The Time-Keepers are monitoring every aspect of this case.
我从没见过他们这么在意
I've never seen them so involved.
他们想要抓住那个时间犯
They want that Variant caught.
我也一样
So do I.
这是你和这个洛基在一起最后的机会
And this is the last chance you're gonna get with this Loki.
没问题 这就足够了
Great. That's all I'm gonna need.
谢谢你 洛斯蕾尔
Thank you, R Slayer.
富兰克林 D 罗斯福高中
这个我也没印象
I don't remember this.
这肯定是你喜欢的那个分析师给的
This must be from that analyst you keep on the side.
别胡思乱想
Stay focused.
我专注着呢
Eyes on the road.
莫比乌斯？
RAVONNA: Mobius?
我差点就走了
I was almost gone.
你真的相信这个时间犯吗？
You really believe in this Variant?
Mmm... Luckily, he believes in himself enough for the both of us.
幸运的是 对于咱俩而言 他足够相信自己
而且如果行不通 我会亲手删除他
And, hey, if it doesn't work, I'll delete him myself.
他真的很自负
He's really arrogant.
你可能想知道任务中到底是怎么回事
You're probably wondering what happened out on the mission.
那就是你抓住洛基的第一课
That was your first lesson in catching a Loki.
掌控他人的预期
Expect the expected.
欺骗一半的乐趣来自于
Half the fun of being a trickster
知道大家都知道你是骗子 然后
is knowing everyone knows you're a trickster, and then,
很多骗术就可以基于
many of your tricks can come from exploiting
-你知道他们知道这个事实… -行了 闭嘴吧！
-the fact that you know that they know... -Okay. Just shut up!
拜托 那个之前和我一起坐电梯的人呢？
Please. What happened to the guy I met on the elevator?
那人不爱说话 你记得吗？
Who didn't like to talk. Remember him?
怎么就变成现在这样了
Now I'm stuck with this guy
没完没了地唠叨洛基的动机
who won't stop yacking away about what makes a Loki tick!
什么意思？ 这不就是我该干的吗？
What? Isn't that precisely why I'm here?
不是 你什么动机我不关心
No. I don't care what makes you tick.
你得帮我抓到更高等的你
You're here to help me catch the superior version of yourself.
-这就够了 -等等
-That's it! -Hang on.
“更高等”这个词用得不恰当吧
I'm not sure "superior" is actually quite the right word.
你看？又来了 就是这样
See? There it is. Right there.
我愚蠢地认为
I believed, stupidly,
那种需要证明自己的不安全感 会让你有动力抓到凶手
that insecure need for validation would motivate you to find the killer.
不是因为你在乎时间变异管理局的任务 或者愿意当什么英雄
Not 'cause you care about the TVA mission or bein' a hero,
而是因为你知道这个时间犯比你厉害 你接受不了这个事实
but because you know this Variant is better than you and you can't take it.
说得好
Very nice.
我的意思是 想要操控我 你也太天真了
I mean, it is adorable that you think you could possibly manipulate me.
我至少比你多算计十步
I'm ten steps ahead of you.
我可一直有我自己的打算
I've been playing a game of my own all along.
你想干嘛？在时间守护者面前花言巧语
What, charm your way in front of the Time-Keepers,
哄骗他们 然后控制时间变异管理局？
hustle them, and seize control of the TVA?
我猜得对吗？
Am I getting warm?
史上最厉害的骗子的经典骗术
A double cross by history's most reliable liar.
好吧 那你为什么在里面 还要为我冒险担保？
Okay. Why are you in there sticking your neck out for me?
我给你两个原因
I'll give you two options,
你爱信哪个信哪个
and you can believe whichever one you want.
其一 因为我看到一个被吓坏的小男孩 在寒风中瑟瑟发抖
A, because I see a scared little boy, shivering in the cold.
谁还没点恻隐之心呢
And you kinda feel bad for that ice runt.
或者其二 我就是想抓住那家伙
Or B, I just wanna catch this guy,
所以该告诉你的 我一字不差地告诉你
and I'll tell you whatever I need to tell you.
我不需要你的怜悯
I don't need your sympathy.
好极了 因为我的怜悯也快没了
Good, 'cause I'm runnin' out of it.
什么意思？ 这是为了操控我的下一步...
What's this? Next step of your manipulation...
这是最后一步 你最后的机会
This is the final step. Your last chance.
我最后的机会需要干点什么？
Oh, and what does my desperate last chance require?
干活
Work.
干活？
Work?
我需要你去重新看一遍 每个时间犯的卷宗
I need you to go over each and every one of the Variant's case files,
然后 给我你的... 怎么说来着？
and then, give me your... How do I put it?
你独特的洛基视角
Your unique Loki perspective.
谁知道呢？ 没准我们真有漏看的东西
And who knows? Maybe there's something that we missed.
你们这群笨蛋 漏掉的东西肯定不少
Well, you're idiots. I suspect you probably missed a lot.
要不说有你在算我走运呢
That's why I'm lucky I got ya for a little bit longer.
你就在这开始吧
Let me park ya at this desk.
一定要不辞辛劳全情投入
And don't be afraid to really lean into this work.
给你个小建议
Here's a good trick for you.
就当这份工作攸关性命
Pretend your life depends on it.
我去吃点东西
I'm gonna get a snack.
我的天啊
Oh, my goodness.
这个时间犯不会又偷袭杀害了 一队时间卫士吧
Don't tell me the Variant ambushed and killed another team of Minutemen.
And stole their reset charge as well.
而且还又偷走了重置器
Shh.
嗨
Hi.
你好？
Hello?
需要帮忙吗？
Can I help you?
是的 我正在进行 重要的时间变异管理局工作
Yes. I'm on some important TVA business.
我跟着他们一起外出行动 你知道行动是什么样的
Follow-up to a field mission. You know how it goes.
那个红线就快到峰值了…
We red lined near the apex, and...
好吧 这行不通
Well, it's never good.
我需要所有关于 时间变异管理局创立的文件
Um, I'd like all files pertaining to the creation of the TVA, please.
那些是机密
Those are classified.
好吧 那就给我所有 关于时间起始的文件吧
Okay. I'd like all files pertaining to the beginning of time then.
-那些是机密 -好吧 时间尽头的也行
-Those are classified. -Okay, the end of time.
-那些是机密 -好吧 什么文件我能看？
-Those are classified. -Okay, what files can I have?
祝你读得开心
Happy reading.
时间犯卷宗 姓名：劳菲森 洛基
时间查询 阿斯加德毁灭事件 细节
诸神的黄昏（七级末日）
星球完全毁灭
没有检测到时间犯能量 取代时间
整个文明灭绝
伤亡人数 9719
没有检测到时间犯能量 取代时间
我发现了些东西
I found something.
不对 我说过了 “在读完所有卷宗前别来烦我”
No, I said, "Don't bother me until you've read all the files."
-我读完了 -所有卷宗？
-I have. -Every file?
-是的 -所有和时间犯有关的？
-Yes. -Pertaining to the Variant?
答案不在卷宗里 而是在时间线上
The answer isn't in the files, it's on the timeline.
他藏在末日里
He's hiding in apocalypses.
哪个末日？
Which apocalypse?
历史上随便哪个？ 大概得有一百万个吧
Any time in history? There's, like, a million of 'em.
诸神的黄昏 你知道吗？
Ragnarok. Are you familiar?
是的 阿斯加德和几乎 所有子民的覆灭 请节哀
Yes. The destruction of Asgard and most of its people. I'm sorry.
是的 非常伤感
Yes, very sad.
随便吧 我有个想法…
Anyway, it got me thinking...
接着说
Go ahead.
关连事件
Nexus events
出现是因为某人做了不该做的事 对吗？
happen when someone does something they're not supposed to do, right?
可能更复杂点 但基本上是吧
Well, it's a little more complicated, but, yeah.
好 然后他们不该做的那些事
Great. And then that thing they're not supposed to do,
会引发一系列不该发生的连锁反应
cascades into a whole range of other things that aren't supposed to happen.
然后不断继续 直到出现一个新的时间分支 对吗？
And so on and so forth, until eventually, a new timeline branches. Yes?
对于既定结果的混乱改动
Chaotic alterations of a predetermined outcome.
-没错 所以 假设… -你要干什么？
-Exactly. So, let's just say... -Mmm-hmm. What are you doing?
你的沙拉就是阿斯加德
...your salad is Asgard in this scenario.
-这不是阿斯加德 这是我的午饭 -我打个比方
-It's not Asgard, that's my lunch. -It's a metaphor.
-先别急 -我想吃那个沙拉
-Just hang in there. -I want that salad.
我可以去阿斯加德
And I could go down to Asgard
在诸神的黄昏完全毁灭一切之前
before Ragnarok causes its complete destruction
我想干什么就干什么
and I could do anything I wanted.
我可以 比如说 把浩克从彩虹桥推下去
I could, let's say, push the Hulk off the Rainbow Bridge.
-他掉下去了 -盐就是浩克？
-There he goes. -The salt's Hulk?
我还可以… 把宫殿给烧掉
And I could also... Set fire to the palace.
不要 住手 别把宫殿给烧掉
No, just stop. Don't set fire to the palace.
明白了吗？我想干什么就干什么 不会有任何影响
Okay? I can do whatever I want to do, and it would never matter.
一切都不会违背既定的时间线 因为…
It wouldn't go against the dictates of the timeline because...
-打扰一下 -天啊！
-Excuse me? -MOBIUS: Oh, God!
-是你 -很高兴见到你
-You! -Nice to see you.
借用一下 谢谢
I just need this for a second. Thanks.
因为反正末日就要来了
Because the apocalypse is coming.
诸神的黄昏 无论我做什么 苏尔特尔都会毁灭阿斯加德
Ragnarok, Surtur will destroy Asgard no matter what I do.
不 别毁啊…
No, don't do...
-末日到来了 -那是末日吗？
LOKI: There's the apocalypse. MOBIUS: That's the apocalypse?
诸神的黄昏抹掉了盐的存在
Ragnarok obliterates the salt.
诸神的黄昏
Ragnarok.
就是这意思
There it is.
我到底在看什么？
What am I lookin' at?
好吧 这个比喻有点简单粗暴 但是你明白我的意思
Okay, it was a clumsy metaphor. But you see what I mean.
无所谓的 可能是任何一个末日
It doesn't matter. It could be any apocalypse.
可能是海啸巨浪 可能是陨石
It could be a tidal wave. It could be a meteor.
还可能是火山爆发 或者超新星爆炸
It could be a volcano, a supernova.
如果周围的所有人或者事物都注定立刻毁灭
If everything and everyone around you is destined for imminent destruction,
那我说什么或者做什么都无所谓
then nothing that I say or do will matter,
因为时间线不会出现分支
because the timeline's not gonna branch.
因为这条时间线被毁灭了
'Cause it gets destroyed.
因此 时间犯可能就藏在末日之中
Hence, the Variant could be hiding in the apocalypse
他可以随心所欲 我们也无从得知
and do whatever he wants, and we wouldn't know!
不错
Not bad.
带我去个真的末日 去诸神的黄昏吧 我展示给你看
Take me to a real apocalypse, to Ragnarok, I'll show you.
好啊 然后你就可以跑回老家去了？你休想
Yeah. So you can run away back to your homeland? No.
不 我没想回家 咱们去哪都行
No, I'm not going home. We can go anywhere.
我连海滨公园散步都不会带你去 末日就更别提了
I'm not taking you for a stroll along the promenade, much less an apocalypse.
莫比乌斯 别这样
Oh, Mobius, come on!
能有什么问题呢？
What could possibly go wrong?
咱们得测试一下这个理论
We gotta properly test this theory.
我倒是有个有趣的理论
Well, here's a fun theory.
你诱惑我外出行动 然后在背后捅我一刀
You lure me out into the field, and stab me in the back.
这个理论我可不想冒险
And that's a theory I don't wanna test.
我从来没在背后捅过人
I'd never stab anyone in the back.
这种背叛也太没创意了
That's such a boring form of betrayal.
洛基 我研究过你这一生的每个时刻
Loki, I've studied almost every moment of your entire life.
你在背后捅人 少说得有五十次
You've literally stabbed people in the back, like, 50 times.
那我绝对不会再捅了 因为这太老套了
Well, I'd never do it again, because it got old.
Okay.
好吧
好吧 那这样 你可以不相信我 但是你得相信一点
Okay, look, you don't trust me, you can trust one thing.
我喜欢证明我是对的
I love to be right.
意大利 庞贝
公元79年
-准备开始了 -随时都有可能
- Here we go. -Shh, any minute now.
整个城镇会被从这个星球抹掉
Until this entire town is wiped off the face of this planet.
想象一下 那些火山灰…
Imagine. All that volcanic ash...
我知道 咱们也不用那么兴奋吧
I know. We don't want to get too giddy.
来嘛 多酷啊
Oh, come on! It's cool.
确实很酷 但是不那么好受 因为...
No, it is cool, but it's just not in good taste because...
反正他们怎么着都会死
They're all gonna die anyway.
我知道 听我说 我就盯着传送器上的变异能量
I know. Now listen, I'm gonna watch the TemPad for any variance energy.
-好的 -好的 因为我们得小心行事
-Okay. -Okay, because we gotta be careful.
如果你错了 而且很有可能你会错
If you're wrong, and there's a good chance you are,
我们的所作所为会导致一个巨大的时间分支
anything we do can create a huge branch.
莫比乌斯 世界末日都让你搞得索然无味了
Oh, Mobius! You make even the end of the world sound boring.
听着 好吧 我们就不该在这里
Listen! Okay, we're not meant to be here.
-好吗？ -好吧
-Okay? -Okay.
我们的动作可能会影响历史进程
Anything we do can impact the course of history.
-你明白吗？ -明白 明白
-Do you get that? -Yes. Yes.
所以咱们得从非常小的干扰开始
So we're gonna start with very small disturbances.
-非常小的 -你会鸟叫吗？
-Very small. -Can you make bird noises?
鸟叫？
Bird noises?
是啊 鸟叫 就是那种从嘴里吹气的声音
Yeah. Bird noises. Like some, like, whooshing noises.
--Oh.
洛基 洛基
Loki! Loki!
--Go!
走吧！
享受自由吧 头上长角的朋友 你们自由了
Be free, my horned-friends, be free!
我叫洛基
我们是时间变异管理局的特工
我给你们带来了黑暗的消息
你们所有人！
都要葬身于此
那座火山即将喷发！
我能知道是因为我来自未来
我们是来自未来的 对吧？
We are from the future, right?
时间变异管理局是什么？ 我的意思是 它来自于未来
What is the TVA? I mean, it's from the future.
听着就特别未来 真的很有未来感
It sounds from the future. It's pretty future-y.
时间刚刚好！
Right on cue!
享受你们的最后一餐吧
Enjoy your last meal while you can!
一切都不重要了！
Nothing matters!
不会有任何后果！
Nothing has any consequence!
趁着没死继续跳舞吧！
Dance while you still can!
- Whoo-hoo! -
情况如何？
How'd we do?
难以置信 变异能量为零
I don't believe it. Zero variance energy.
也没有产生时间分支
No branching in the timeline.
时间变异管理局根本不知道咱们在这里
The TVA would never even know we were here.
如果是我的话 这就是我的藏身之处
If it were me, this is where I would hide.
是末日 时间犯偷袭我们的士兵
Doomsdays. The Variant's been ambushing our soldiers
然后藏在末日里 隐匿行踪
and hiding out in doomsdays to cover his tracks.
-不用谢 -好
-You're welcome. -Yeah.
要让这个理论成立 灾难就应该是
For this theory to hold, the disasters have to be
自然发生的 突如其来的 毫无征兆的 无人幸免的
naturally-occurring, sudden, no warning, no survivors.
-有多少符合条件的？ -我不知道
-How many could there be? -I don't know.
我们会知道的
We're gonna find out.
嘿？
Hey?
来吧 咱们一起走走
Come on, let's take a walk.
话说 你桌上的那本杂志
By the way, at your desk, that magazine?
有摩托艇那本？
Yeah. The one on jet skis?
是的
Yes.
你要那个干什么？
Why do you have that?
因为它们棒极了
Because they're awesome.
- I suppose they are. -Yeah.
-我知道 -是
有些东西…其实历史上大多数东西都挺蠢的
You know, some things... Actually, most things in history are kinda dumb,
而且最终一切都会湮灭
and everything gets ruined eventually.
但是在九十年代初期 有一段短暂的辉煌
But in the early 1990s, for a brief, shining moment,
那是外形与功能的美丽统一
there was a beautiful union of form and function,
那就是摩托艇
which we call the jet ski,
任何有理智的人都会感同身受
and a reasonable man cannot differ.
你骑过吗？
You ever been on one?
没有…没有
No... No.
如果时间变异管理局的特工 骑着摩托艇出现在神圣的时间线上
I think a TVA agent showing up on a jet ski on the Sacred Timeline,
一定会产生时间分支
that would create a branch for sure.
不过肯定很有趣
It'd be fun, though.
是的 绝对很有趣
Yeah, it'd be really fun.
所以 为什么看那些？
So, why read about them?
就是提醒我自己 我们是为什么而奋斗
Just helps remind me of what we're fighting for.
我的意思是 你对这一切都深信不疑 对不对？
I mean, you really believe in all this stuff, don't you?
我不会在 “相信或不相信” 这件事上纠结
I don't get hung up on, "Believe, not believe."
我就是接受了这一切
I just accept what is.
-三只魔法蜥蜴 -是时间守护者
-Three magic lizards... -Time-Keepers.
-创造了时间变异管理局和这里所有的人 -没错
-...created the TVA, and everyone in it... -Right.
-也包括你？ -也包括我
-...including you? -Including me.
每一次我想夸你聪明的时候
Every time I start to admire your intelligence,
-你就开始说这种话 -好吧 是谁创造的你 洛基？
-you say something like that. -Okay, who created you, Loki?
约顿海姆的冰霜巨人
A Frost Giant of Jotunheim.
那是谁养育的你呢？
And who raised you?
阿斯加德的奥丁
Odin of Asgard.
奥丁 天界之神
Odin, God of the Heavens.
阿斯加德 神秘的国度 远在星辰大海
Asgard, mystical realm, beyond the stars.
-冰霜巨人 你自己听听… -这不一样
-Frost Giants. Listen to yourself... -It's not the same.
-这完全不一样啊 -不
-It's completely different. -No.
-这不是一回事 -这就是一回事
-It's not the same. -It's exactly the same thing.
因为如果深究我们从哪里来的问题
Because if you think too hard about where any of us came from,
我们到底是什么的问题 听起来都有点荒谬
who we truly are, it sounds kinda ridiculous.
存在即混乱
Existence is chaos.
没什么是有意义的 所以我们就试着寻找意义
Nothing makes any sense, so we try to make some sense of it.
我很幸运 我出身的混乱赐予了我这一切…
And I'm just lucky that the chaos I emerged into gave me all this...
我的光荣使命
- My own glorious purpose. -
时间变异管理局就是我的生命
'Cause the TVA is my life.
它是真实的 因为我相信它是真实的
And it's real because I believe it's real.
行吧 你相信它是真实的
Fair enough. You believe it's real.
是的
Yeah.
所以一切都是注定的
So everything is written.
过去 现在 将来
Past, present, future.
根本就没有什么自由意志
There's no such thing as free will.
我觉得 这种说法过于简化了
Well, I mean, you know, it's an oversimplification...
所以 事实上 可以这么说
So, in fact, in a way,
在时间变异管理局这里 你我是唯一真正自由的
you and I here at the TVA, we're the only ones who are actually free.
你到底想说什么 洛基？
Where are you going with this, Loki?
那这一切怎么结束？
How does it all end?
工作还没干完呢
That's a work in progress.
Oh, those lazy Time-Keepers. What are they waiting for?
那些懒散的时间守护者 他们在等待什么？
并非如此
Au contraire.
在我们保护过去的时候
No. Because while we protect what came before,
他们正在室内伏案工作
they're toiling away in their chamber,
厘清无限分支中的终极结局
untangling the epilogue from its infinite branches.
我明白了 那当他们完成的时候 会发生什么？
Ah, I see. So, when they're finished, what happens then?
我们的工作也就完成了
So are we.
再也没有关连事件了
No more nexus events.
只有秩序
Just order.
然后我们在时间的尽头平静相见
And we meet in peace at the end of time.
是不是很棒？
Nice, right?
只有秩序？
-Only order? -Mmm-hmm.
没有混乱吗？听起来很无聊
No chaos? It sounds boring.
你肯定觉得无聊
I'm sure it does to you.
你说我是被吓坏的小男孩
You called me a scared little boy.
我说你的可不止这个
I called you a lotta things.
的确如此
You did.
但是你错了
You're wrong, though.
你看 我比孩子知道得多
You see, I know something children don't.
知道什么呢？
What's that?
没有纯粹的坏人
That no one bad is ever truly bad.
也没有纯粹的好人
And no one good is ever truly good.
被吓坏的小男孩
Scared little boy.
是的 你这是自以为高人一等 我其实觉得挺过分的
Yes, it was quite patronizing. I thought it was a bit too far, actually.
没错
你可真聪明
You're very clever.
当然了
I know.
这个时间犯在犯罪现场留下了些东西
The Variant left something behind at an old crime scene.
那是个大教堂 他留下了一个糖果盒
A cathedral. A candy box.
明显不符合那个时代
An obvious anachronism.
我交给分析部了 但是他们没发现什么
I gave it to Analysis, but they couldn't find anything real.
-为什么要提起这个？ -因为这样我们就有两个变量了
-Why does that matter? -'Cause now we have two variables.
末日 自然灾害 以及…
Apocalyptic natural disasters and...
-卡布路易 -那是什么？
-Kablooie. -LOKI: What's that?
是糖果 阿斯加德有糖果吗？
Candy. Do you have candy on Asgard?
有啊 有葡萄和坚果
Yeah. Grapes, nuts.
怪不得你那么苦大仇深的
No wonder you're so bitter.
好吧 卡布路易只有2047年到2051年间 在地球的个别地区发售过
Okay. Kablooie was only sold regionally on Earth from 2047 to 2051.
我们需要对每一个末日事件进行交叉比对
We need to cross-reference that with every apocalyptic event.
这一半你来
I'm gonna give you half.
咱们比比看谁先找到
Have a competition, see who finds it.
-没问题 -你想赌点什么吗？
-Sure. -You wanna bet something?
-好啊 -来一场绅士的赌局
-Yeah. -Gentleman's bet.
是的 赌上我们的骄傲 好的 用实力说话 开始
Yeah, let's play for pride. Okay. May the best man win. Go.
发现什么了吗？
-Anything? -Uh...
肯定不是2048年的气候灾难
It's not the climate disaster of 2048.
也不是2051年的海啸
Or the tsunami of 2051.
赶紧 赶紧 加把劲
Let's go. Let's go. Come on.
2050年
2050.
燕子灭绝了…那是什么？
The extinction of the swallow... Is that a thing?
整个生态系统都完蛋了
Completely screwed up the ecosystem.
喀拉喀托火山在2049年也爆发了
Krakatoa erupted in 2049 as well.
没发现卡布路易
No Kablooie.
天啊 坏事一件接一件 是不是？
God, it's just one damn thing after another, isn't it?
-飓风、饥荒、火山爆发、洪水… -找到了
-Cyclone, famine, volcanoes, floods... -Got him.
末日事件报告
-That's where he is. -MOBIUS: Alabama, 2050.
-他应该在这里 -阿拉巴马州 2050年
我得当心你以后会抢了我的饭碗
You're gonna take my job if I'm not careful.
你想让我批准派出一支全副武装的小队…
You want me to approve deployment of a fully-armed task force to...
-是的 -去时间犯可能的藏身处？
-Yeah. -...the Variant's potential hiding spot?
阿拉巴马州黑文山 那是个自治市
Haven Hills, Alabama, corporate town
属于罗克斯卡特 后来一场飓风将该市完全摧毁
owned by Roxxcart until it's wiped out by a hurricane.
那里的食物和补给充足
All the food and supplies you need.
只要他愿意
If he likes it, there's no reason
他就没有理由不回去 他可以把那里反复当作据点
he can't keep going back and just camping out, over and over.
而且这些理论都来自于
And this is all based on a theory from the Variant
-那个上次搞砸任务的时间犯？ -是的 他干得不错
-who just blew your previous mission? -Yeah, he's doing great.
莫比乌斯 作为你的朋友
Mobius, as your friend,
我必须得告诉你 相信这个人可不明智
I have to tell you that trusting this man is not a good idea.
我知道 但是也许值得一试
No. I know. But maybe he's worth the trouble.
他刚刚发现了咱们安保的巨大漏洞
He just uncovered a huge hole in our security.
我担心的就是这个
That's what concerns me!
我能搞定他 相信我
I can handle him. Trust me.
我们要抓的人就在那里
This is where we get our guy.
我相信你 但是他
You, I trust, but him.
听着 拉沃娜 我的直觉告诉我
Listen, Ravonna, every instinct is telling me
在那里肯定能抓到这个时间犯
this is where we nail the Variant.
批准吧 你从来没见我这么激动过 是不是？
Come on. You don't see me usually this worked up, right?
我兴奋极了
I'm excited.
我都迫不及待了
I'm chomping at the bit.
-好吧 -太好了
-Okay. -Yes. Okay.
-但是 莫比乌斯 -是的？
-But, Mobius? -Yeah?
如果这次还是不行 我就帮不了你了
There's not much I can do if it doesn't work out.
永恒
For all time.
常相伴
Always.
好的
Okay.
咱们出动
We're on.
咱们今天干得漂亮
We are doing some good work today.
我也这么觉得
I thought so too.
我跟你说 你要是真能帮我们抓住这个时间犯
I'm tellin' you. You actually help us catch this Variant,
也许吧 我的朋友
and who knows, my friend.
怎么着 能让我和时间守护者见面吗？
What, good enough for a face-to-face with the Time-Keepers?
我可没那么说
I didn't say that.
-一步一步来吧 -好吧 一步一步来
-One step at a time. -All right. One step at a time.
-以防万一 -太好了 这感觉让人…
-Just in case. -Yeah, don't those feel...
绝对不行
Absolutely not.
集合 准备任务简报
Gather around for a briefing.
罗克斯卡特是个超大型超市 在那个时代很常见
Roxxcart is a vast superstore common to the era.
整个建筑由许多分区组成
It consists of a series of sprawling sections,
还有一个巨大的仓库
including a large warehouse.
这个仓库在飓风期间变成了民众的避难所
This warehouse is being used by civilians as a shelter tryin' to ride out the storm.
记住 这可是十级的末日事件
Remember, this is a class ten apocalypse.
虽然时间犯不知道我们会出现
While the Variant shouldn't know we're coming,
但是他可能藏在任何地方 并且很可能发动攻击
he could be hiding anywhere and should be considered hostile.
请务必保持警惕
So stay alert.
这个时间犯每次袭击后 都会偷走重置器
Every time there is an attack, the Variant steals a reset charge.
他肯定有所图谋
He's planning something.
只是我们还不知道
We just don't know what.
所以一定要留意那些重置器
So keep an eye out for the missing charges,
如果你看到洛基 直接裁剪
and if you see a Loki, prune it.
注意 是那个坏的洛基
The bad Loki, preferably.
阿拉巴马州 黑文山
罗克斯卡特出品
2050年
罗克斯卡特
有情况吗？
Anything?
暂时没有 出发！
Nothing yet. Move out!
这是怎么回事？
The hell was that?
我在用魔法烘干衣服
That was me using magic to dry my clothes.
我又不是你们 每走一步都得大喊大叫的
So I don't announce myself with every squeaky footstep like the rest of you.
HUNTER B-15: Take both teams and sweep the storm shelter.
带上两支队伍去搜查风暴避难所
-遵命 长官 -洛基和我一起
-Yes, ma'am. -MOBIUS: Loki and I are gonna
去查看那个温室 咱们在那边…
check out the Green House. We'll meet...
-不行 -不行？
-No. -No?
你和D-90一起行动 他得跟着我
You go with D-90. He stays with me.
你说什么… 我得全程监视着他
What are you... He's under my supervision.
这次行动我说了算 莫比乌斯
This is my field op, Mobius.
-如果他不构成威胁 就没事… -他当然构成威胁
-If he's not a threat, then... -Of course he's a threat.
-你还记得时间剧场吗？ -莫比乌斯…
-Remember the Time Theater? -Mobius...
-这就是为什么我需要他跟我一起 -你可以回时间变异管理局
-I want him with me. -You are welcome to go back
to the TVA and litigate with Renslayer, but right now...
找洛斯蕾尔去提意见 但是现在…
我们都到这里了 我们不会回去
We're here. We're not going back.
-时间犯就在这里 -莫比乌斯 没关系的
-The Variant is here. -Mobius, it's fine. It's fine.
你可以相信我
You can trust me.
我明白 信任是需要争取的 我会努力的
I understand I have to earn that, so, I will.
为什么那些根本不能信任的人 总是把“相信我”挂在嘴边上？
Why is it the people you can't trust are always saying, "Trust me"?
好吧 这次得一直戴着时间项圈
Okay, try to hang on to your Time Collar this time.
咱们在展厅见
We'll see you in the showroom.
很高兴能和你在一起
I am glad we're getting to spend this time together.
安静
- Quiet. -
我想说咱们是不是走错了…
-I'm saying we got off on the wrong... -Shh.
嘿!
HUNTER B-15: Hey!
别激动
Whoa, whoa. It's okay. It's okay.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
买绿植
Shopping for plants.
在这个暴风天？
In this storm?
暴风天有特价
It's a hurricane sale.
杜鹃花打五折
Azaleas are half off.
Could that be you?
是你吗？
我觉得 我可能会穿得更正式些 但是 没错 也许吧
I mean, I probably would have worn a suit, but, yes, maybe.
他死了吗？
Is he dead?
没有 一般都能活下来
No. They usually survive.
所以你就是时间变异管理局找来 追捕我的那个笨蛋
So, you're the fool the TVA brought in to hunt me down.
应该是我吧
Me, I presume.
拜托 每个人都有身份 你就是我
Please. If anyone's anyone, you're me.
见到你真开心
How nice to meet you.
过去的一小时里 风力在增强
NEWS ANCHOR: For the past hour we have seen winds intensifying.
再说一遍 如果你刚看到 我们有两个...
- Again, if you're just tuning in... -
检查一下包里有没有重置器
HUNTER D-90: Check the bags for the reset charges.
你们是联邦应急管理署的吗？
You guys FEMA?
还是国民警卫队？
National Guard?
可能是他们中的任何人
Could be any one of them.
如果你们有直升飞机或者其它交通工具
Well, hey, if you got a 'copter or other transport,
现在该派上用场了
now is the time to use it.
这里有女人和小孩 这天气可不是闹着玩的
We got women and kids, and that weather ain't playin'.
抱歉 我们没有
No, I'm sorry. We don't.
那你们是怎么来的？
Well, how the heck did you get here?
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
你吓到他们了
Hey! These people are scared.
他们快要死了 他们本来就应该害怕
They're about to die. They should be scared.
但不是害怕我们
Okay. Not of us.
-先生 -别着急
-Sir! -Take it easy.
怎么了？
What is it?
这是真的 这是真的 这是真的
HUNTER C-20:  It's real. It's real. It's real.
It's real. It's real. It's real.
附身这一招挺聪明
Enchantment is a clever trick.
有点懦弱 有点业余 但是挺聪明
Cowardly, a bit amateur-ish, but clever.
和为时间变异管理局工作一样懦弱
Almost as cowardly as working for the TVA.
我是为我自己工作的
I'm working for me.
You really believe that, don't you?
-你还真信了 是不是？ -对
Yeah.
我还担心他们找到了一个更高等的我呢
And here I was worried that they'd found a better version of me.
你们是在找避难所吗？
Hi, are you guys looking for the disaster shelter?
不是
No.
THE VARIANT: Oh, bless.
老天保佑
你要向你那些小朋友求救吗？
Are you going to call your little friends for help?
怎么了？
LOKI: What's the matter?
你害怕和我面对面吗？
You too scared to meet me face-to-face?
现身吧
Show yourself.
得到他们的信任可不容易
You know, gaining their confidence was no mean feat.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
你是在卧底
You went undercover.
如果你稍微收敛一下
If you could possibly sheathe your smarm for a moment,
我就告诉你我来找你的原因
I have an offer for you. That's why I found you.
继续说
Go on.
我要推翻时间守护者
I'm going to overthrow the Time-Keepers.
我跟你摊牌
And, uh, cards on the table,
我需要一个合格的副官
I could use a qualified lieutenant.
我猜你说的是…我？
And I assume you mean... Me?
你觉得呢
What say you...
洛基？
Loki?
Ugh. Don't call me that.
别那么叫我
你可以叫我
You can call me...
兰迪
Randy.
天啊 我算明白为什么索尔 觉得这很烦了
God. Now I understand why Thor found this so annoying.
别耍我了 我可是在帮你
Enough with your games. I've been trying to help you.
在文艺复兴市集上 我可是帮你拖延了不少时间
I kept them vulnerable at the Renaissance Fair for some time.
天啊 太感谢你了
Oh, gosh, and that was just so nice of you.
但是考虑了八到十秒以后
But after eight to ten seconds of consideration,
我的答案是否定的
the answer is no.
我对统治时间变异管理局毫无兴趣
I'm not interested in ruling the Time Variance Authority.
这是真的 这是真的
HUNTER C-20: It's real. It's real.
It was real. It was real.
-什么是真的？什么... -这是真的
-What's real? What's... -It's real.
-她疯了 -这是真的
-She's off the dial. -It's real.
-看着我 -这是真的
-MOBIUS: Look at me. -It's real.
我想回家
I wanna go home.
我们会带你回家
We're gonna get you there.
呼叫时间变异管理局 通知医务室
Call the TVA, let the infirmary know...
不不不 我说出去了
No, no, no. I gave it away.
-我说出去了 -你说出去什么了？
-I gave it away. -What did you give away...
时间守护者 他们的位置
The Time-Keepers, where they are.
我把找到他们的方法说出去了
I gave it away how to find them.
B-15 你那边情况如何？
B-15, what is your status?
B-15 请回话 你那边什么情况？
B-15, come in. What's your status?
B-15 你能听到吗？
B-15, do you copy?
如果你不想统治时间变异管理局 那你想干什么？
If you don't wanna rule the TVA, then what do you want?
这不重要 你来得太晚了
It doesn't matter. You're too late.
你会发现我永远是抢占先机的
I think you'll find I'm well ahead of schedule.
我就是这样找到你的藏身之处的
I found your hiding place like that.
我觉得我才是更高等的洛基 你说呢？
I'd say that makes me the superior Loki, wouldn't you?
I see. That's your plan.
我明白了 那是你的计划
把我们引到这里 然后炸掉这个地方
Lure us all here so you can blow the place up.
我想念兰迪
I miss Randy.
谢谢你帮我拖延时间
Thank you for helping me stall for time.
你真的很喜欢自说自话
You really do love to hear yourself talk.
You're the first person to tell me that.
以前还没人跟我这么说过
我永远也不会这样对待自己
I would never treat me like this.
你好
Hi.
来吧 别藏着了
Oh, come on. Stop hiding.
洛基 你要是还要脸 就自己来和我打
Loki, if you had any honor you'd fight me as yourself.
我忙着呢
I have shit to do.
够了
Enough!
-莫比乌斯 -他在哪？
-HUNTER B-15: Mobius. -Where is he?
-我跟丢了 -发生了什么？
-I lost him. -What happened?
我...
I...
看来你心爱的洛基背叛了你
Looks like your favorite Loki betrayed you.
快点行动
MOBIUS: Just move!
你想从我这得到什么？
What do you want from me?
这是怎么回事？
What is this about?
做好心理准备吧 洛基
THE VARIANT: Brace yourself, Loki.
LOKI:  What do you want from me?
你想从我这得到什么？
What do you want from me?
这是怎么回事？
What is this about?
你想从我这得到什么？
What do you want from me?
这是怎么回事？
What is this about?
你想从我这得到什么？
What do you want from me?
这是怎么回事？
What is this about?
这和你没关系
This isn't about you.
没错
Right.
启动
正在初始化
它们去哪了？
Where they going?
这不可能
That's not possible.
我是分析师1182-E 报告代码000
This is Analyst 1182-E, uh, reporting a code, uh, 000.
时间分支正在快速形成 斜率...
Branches rapidly forming at a slope...
有人攻击了神圣时间线
Somebody just bombed the Sacred Timeline.
洛基
MOBIUS: Loki!
洛基 等等
Loki, wait!
等等 洛基 等等
Wait! Loki, wait!
不要 等等 洛基
No! Wait, Loki!
该死
Damn it!
根据漫威漫画改编
漫威影业出品
字幕翻译：虫二